

Ishtiaq Mahmood Amin

ANDROID DEVELOPER · SOFTWARE ENGINEER

A-6, 543, East Kazipara, Mirpur-1216, Dhaka, Bangladesh

□ (+880) 1781-106123 | 🗷 i4idrhine@gmail.com | 🖸 IronBlossom | 😫 IronBlossom | 🥦 IronBlossom

"The true delight is in the finding out rather than in the knowing." -Isaac Asimov

Summary

Current Android/React Native Developer at Offshore Software Development company Adaptive Enterprise Limited. Analytical and detail oriented programmer specialized in android development, socket programming and both Object-oriented & Functional programming. A reader, teamworker with steller communication skill who loves Linux, android kernel customization and enjoys tweaking the development environment to its efficiency. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks and learning new technologies and tools when needed.

Work Experience _

Adaptive Enterprise Limited

Dhaka, Bangladesh

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Dec. 2014 - Present

- Developed, supervised and currently maintaining more than 7 of NAPCO Security Technologies biggest state of the art apps to manage home security, home automation, video cameras on Android and React Native utilizing Socket Programming(TCP and UDP), Serial port communication (NDK), H.264 video decoding, Bluetooth Low Energy, IPC, Google Vision api, Realm for Android etc.
- Implemented an in-house stock exchange analysis app with seamless UX/UI maintaining the Material Design guidelines with tools like MPAndroidChart, SVG.
- Designed and developing a React Native app, that aggregates several reputated government/non-government banks, to make a secured payment rail in the national e-commerce field under DOER.
- · Visited NAPCO and worked with their Firmware and Backend developers to accelerate/stabilize development of running projects.

Cloudwell Limited Dhaka, Bangladesh

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Aug. 2013 - Dec. 2014

- Developed 5 easy-to-use Android apps for the startup, facilitating Paywell's Payment infrastructure from Paywell Services app to in-house applications e.g. Paywell Distributor/Dealer/Collector/Territory Officer app.
- Provisioned backend developers with Servlet +php/Java bridge +Quartz Job Scheduler and by building an app that acts as a tiny sms server for TeleTalk REB Bill Payment.
- Java Desktop application (jdk1.6+ JavaFX) that pushes sms utilizing SilverStreet sms gateway.
- Worked with Telpo and partially developed Paywell application (with the provided SDK on Embedded-C) on 3 different embedded subsystem POS terminals (TPS300, KMY801B, MIL300)

AnnaNovas IT Dhaka, Bangladesh

SOFTWARE ENGINEER (ANDROID)

Oct. 2011 - Jun. 2013

- Built several apps using REST api, SQLite, custom views/controls, Google Maps API (v2), FCM/GCM(then Google C2DM) etc from ground up.
- Developed 4 inbuilt system apps and the launcher app that executes Linux shell commands for Polaroid Kids Tablet.

Projects_

iBridge

Android +NDK +Socket +AIDL +Digest Auth +Streaming H.264 +Realm for Android +Google Vision api

- NAPCO's state-of-the-art security/access control app for intrusion detection, fire alarms, IoT available in Wireless(local & remote) and panel-wired IBR-TOUCH tablet versions.
- Smart Z-Wave[™] device automation of indoor and outdoor lights, dimmers, thermostats, locks with scene creation, triggered events & scheds.
- Integrated top branded panel's keypad like ADT®/Honeywell®, DSC®.

iLock Android +Bluetooth LE

NAPCO Alarm Lock division's smartphone Bluetooth LE solution for unlocking(/locking for Canadian market) proprietary Trilogy®Networx™
 ArchiTech™ Series Designer Access Control Locks from android device without the need to carry cumbersome ID cards or keys.

Virtual Keypad & StarLink

Android +OkHttp +Socket +AIDL

- Virtual Keypad Conventional keypad screen and keypad-programming for renowned security keypad manufacturer e.g. ADT®/Honeywell®
- StarLink Universal intrusion alarm reporting mobile solution with Arming/Disarming capabilities on panels.

Click or Tap on the name/tech/topic/product/location text to find out more.

- Kids Vids Proprietary app with age control that streams kids friendly videos from YouTube.
- Kids Start The Launcher app of the tablet with a feature of restricting apps.
- Kids Cam Proprietary app for taking picture and shooting video with built-in fun filters.
- Music Player Audio player app with custom visualizer.
- DJ Studio A little DJ app for kids with fun sounds and beats.
- · Best design and innovation award winner of CES2013. Featured in Engadget, USA TODAY, Digital Trends.

Paywell Services Android+Glide

• Designed for retailers or store owners that want to sell mobile airtime and various utility bills of Bangladesh.

Android Development

Google Maps api +Instagram api +OkHttp +Media Api +Realm for Android +MJPEG +MPAndroidChart

- OneOrchard OneOrchard brings you a whole different online experience as you use the app along Orchard Road, Singapore.
- **Beer Price** Get updated prices, selections, locations and rating from over 3,000 bars in Scandinavia. Both price and selection can easily be updated thorugh the in-app report function.
- Singapore Chinese Orchestra (SCO) Official app for Singapore's only professional Chinese orchestra.
- My Collection Develop for the people who has great passions on regarding there collected Coin, Stamps and Sports Cards.
- MyiSeeVideo iSeeVideo app for Napco's video services for ISEE series cameras.
- Paywell Distributor, Dealer, Collector, Mobile airtime, Territory Officer (In-house) 5 apps satisfying significant aspects of Paywell's bussiness model, distributor-to-dealer-to-retailer, mobile territory manager.
- CSE (In-house) Chittagong Stock Exchange analysis app with animated Line chart and Bar chart.
- Akij BR (In-house) App for sales officers of country's giant Akij Group, to daily market survey and report/generate pdf their fulfilled target to
 a central server

React Native Development

Flexbox +Redux +Redux-Saga

- DoerPay Currently under development, aggregated payment solution app.
- iLock Currently under development, NAPCO's Bluetooth LE solution app in React Native.

Skills_

Development

- Language Java, C, Javascript(ES6), Groovy, C++, Kotlin. (efficiency from left to right)
- Environment, Debugging & IDE Android Studio / IntelliJ IDEA , Firebase , TCP/IP Communication , BLE , ADB+Fastboot , Android Profiler , Layout Inspector , Vector graphics , Gradle build scripting , SQL Server/Oracle 11g + JDBC , REST , SQLite , Code::Blocks , NetBeans , Eclipse , Maven , Cygwin , arm Keil's µVision , Vim , nano.
- Version Control Git+Terminal, GitHub, GitLab, Team Foundation Server.
- **Libraries** Android Support Libraries , Realm for android , Retrofit , OkHttp , ButterKnife , RxJava , Room , Glide , Universal Image Loader , prebuilt static or shared .so/.a libraries.
- Cross-platform React Native, state management with Redux/React-Redux utilizing Redux-Saga, Metro, npm.
- Operating System Any workable environment ranging from Windows, macOS to vanilla Arch / Debian or their stable distros.

Personal

- · Keen attention to detail and a very good listener. Develop, while keeping design patterns in mind.
- Proactive problem solver with an urge to follow best practices. Team-worker, inquisitive, communicable, dedicated to continuously developing, implementing, and adopting new technologies.

Enthusiastic

- PuTTY, Shell scripting in Bash, zsh. completed beginner level Python2.7 on Codeacademy, Decompiling jars and apk.
- Tweaking android device's internals from unlocking bootloader, flashing kernels, optimizing performance.

Education

AUST(Ahsanullah University of Science and Technology)

Dhaka, Bangladesh

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Apr. 2007 - Sep. 2011

• Completed graduation with CGPA 2.97 on a scale of 4.00 from CSE Dept.

Hobbies & Activities

An audiophile, surfing web looking for high fidelity, binaural audio. A poweruser, football fanatic, traveler, bicycler, Rubik's Cuber and avid artenthusiast e.g. photography, photopainting, calligraphy, abstract, low poly.

Regular blood donar.